<book title="Craftologikon" cover="gbook:blank" fontSize="0.6" home="1:2">

    <include ref="gbook:xml/standard.xml"/>

    <chapter id="Preface">
        <section>
            <p bold="true" align="center">
                ..............................
            </p>
            <p bold="true" align="center">
                C O N T E N T S
            </p>
            <space height="20"/>
            <p bold="true">- <link ref="chapter0">Introduction</link></p>
            <p bold="true">- <link ref="chapter1">The Beginning</link></p>
            <p bold="true">- <link ref="chapter2">The Early Game</link></p>
            <p bold="true">- <link ref="chapter3">The Mid Game</link></p>
            <p bold="true">- <link ref="chapter4">The Late Game</link></p>
            <p bold="true">- <link ref="chapter5">The End Game</link></p>
            <p bold="true">- <link ref="chapter6">Modpack Goals (WIP)</link></p>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter id="chapter0">
        <page>
            <title bold="true" underline="true">Introduction</title>
            <p>
                Hello, thank you for downloading my modpack. It has been over a year of development and work without any previous
                knowledge about these things, all of this started in part because one day i decided to change one recipe of my 1.12.2 
                world just because i didn't like how ugly and boring it was, i liked the outcome and then continued to change more and 
                more recipes, and now, after more than 1800 recipes changed i can say i am sort of happy with how things are crafted so 
                i decided to create this modpack to share it with you.
            </p>
            <p>
                I want to thank all the mod devs for doing such nice mods that make me wanting to continue playing Minecraft. But in special 
                thanks to the creators of CraftTweaker and ContentTweaker, without them i wouldn't have created this modpack. 
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
            <p>
                This book is not meant to be a complete guide to lead you through the whole modpack with a questline or an advancements system,
                here you will only find some some small tips and mentions to changes i have made in recipes or in the config that require you to know. 
                If i don't make metion to a mod it just means there is nothing important to say about it. 
            </p>
            <p>
                There is not a strict sequence of actions to complete this modpack, you are free to explore the mods you want in the order you 
                preferand learn your own way of advancing through it. However, crafting recipes talk for themselves, to craft a certain item or 
                block you will need to complete a series of steps before, even though in some cases you have different ways of getting to the 
                same point.   
            </p>
            <p>
                If you notice something really important is missing on this book or you find any sort inconsistency on the recipes or the config, 
                or you find a mod conflict, feel free to report it to the issues page or the discord server.
            </p>
        </page>
    </chapter>
    <chapter id="chapter1">
        <page>
            <title bold="true" underline="true">The Beginning</title>
            <p>           
                You are about to begin your adventure in Craftologia, many of you probably have experience in other modpacks, but if it is your first
                time playing a modpack i warn you that your first steps in this one will be very different of any previous Minecraft world you have 
                played before.
            </p>
            <p>
                You may have noticed that you can't break down trees with your bare hands, of course you need an axe to do so, which means there is no quick
                way of getting wood and cobblestone to start crafting things or go mining one minute after you started this world, actually things require more
                time to be done in this modpack. 
            </p>
            <p>
                First you will need to explore your surroundings to find the materials you need to make your first crafting, which should be the stone pickaxe,
                many of you probably know how to get the resources needed to craft it, there are several ways to get a pickaxe, but i will still recommend you 
                to explore by the riversides.
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
            <p>
                Finding a Village is your best bet, if not abandoned, it will provide you with a variety of food and some useful things for the early game, 
                it is also the perfect place for setting up your first base. 
            </p>
            <p>
                There are also other things you should take into consideration if you want to survive to the first day.
                Days are 60 minutes long, this is three times a normal vanilla day, which may be enough time to find all the materials needed to craft a pickaxe, 
                but pay attention to the food, it is very important in the first days as you will be like a nomad, moving around to find the materials you need, 
                without a permanent base and source of food, raw meat is not healthy, you need to process it. Berries and fruits are a good alternative until you 
                get a furnace. Diversifing your food sources in the first days will be difficult.
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
             <p>
                There are four seasons, each one last 28 days, not like a real season but it will almost feel like one given the fact each day is 1 hour long, 
                you may change this if you want, but having long seasons has some advantages aswell depending the biome and your powergen setup. This should be 
                an important thing to consider when you set up your bases, even more since sleeping does not reset the rain. There are several crops and seeds for 
                each of the seasons so i am sure you can make it during the long winter. 
            </p>
            <p>
                One of the main features of this modpack is oregen, almost all the ores in this modpack have biome-based and/or dimension-based oregen, so you 
                will need to visit almost all the biomes and dimensions if you want to find all of them. Each biome contains several ores, with some exceptions, 
                and each ore can be found in several biomes, with some exceptions. 
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
            <p>
                How do you know where to find a certain ore? Well, exploration should lead you to the answer at some point, but maybe you are too hasty and you
                prefer to spoil yourself checking the modpack files or asking somewhere, that is up to your playstyle, still i recommend you to note down all the 
                ores you find in each biome you visited as you explore the world, it will become handy later on. 
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
            <p bold="true">Chapter Tips</p>
            <p>
                -Sticks can be obtained at early game by breaking leaves and trees, fallen branches in the ground or by crafting from leaves.
            </p>
            <p>
                -String can be obtained from wool, flax and cotton crops, or by killing spiders.
            </p>
            <p>
                -Iron Ores can't be melted down in Vanilla Furnaces, you need a TiC Smeltery instead.
            </p>
            <p>
                -Pickaxes that display diamond mining level are not able to break obsidian blocks, this is not a modification by me, it just means they can mine 
                diamonds.
            </p>
            <p>
                -Melting Villagers in the Smeltery no longer gives you molten emerald.
            </p>
            <p>
                -Villages usually have a Blacksmith and Engineer's House, where you can find an Engineer's Hammer.
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
        </page>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="chapter2">
        <page>
            <title bold="true" underline="true">The Early Game</title>
            <p>
                Even though there is not a questline to keep track of your progress there is a milestone that clearly separates the beginning from the early game, 
                that is the ability to produce steel.
            </p>
            <p>
                At this point in the game you may find yourself having to travel a lot, from one place to another, trying to discover new biomes to get all the 
                resources you need, using a Glider and slime tools will be of great help. As travel distances increase, you can consider setting up multiple small 
                bases over the region instead of having an unique main base to reduce the number of travels you make. At some point you will need to visit new 
                dimensions to acquire certain materials and items that cannot be found in the Overworld. 
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
            <p>
                Dragon Breath may be useful later on, you should carry some bottles with you in your first visit to the End.
                It is highly recommended you obtain ender cores from ender crystals in The End instead of simply breaking them. They will be pretty useful later on. 
                Rushing your fight against the Dragon will deprive you of them.
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
            <p bold="true">Chapter Tips</p>
            <p>
                -Lunch Box allows you to store 6 slots of food to save some inventory space.
            </p>
            <p>
                -To make Aluminium Brass, you can obtain Zinc from Sphalerite Ores in the Crushing Table.
            </p>
            <p>
                -Forge Hammer and Engineer's Hammer can be used in the Magneticraft Crushing Table aswell.
            </p>
            <p>
                -MRUCU entity can also be generated by operating with machines that generate radiation. 
            </p>
            <p>
                -Faucet can be connected to other mods tanks to pour super hot liquids onto the Casting Table.
            </p>
            <p>
                -To create the portal to the Twilight Forest, a MRU Chunk is required instead of a diamond. 
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
        </page>
    </chapter>
    <chapter id="chapter3">
        <page>
            <title bold="true" underline="true">The Mid Game</title>
            <p>
                At this moment you should have visited most of the biomes and dimensions to get the elements needed to progress in the game, its the moment to focus on 
                creating more advanced machines that can process and use all the materials you are gathering. Now you can explore new ways of obtaining resources faster. 
                Power generation becomes an issue now, the most basic generators require materials to run, so using the force of water and wind in your favor will give 
                you a small but constant resource of power.
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
            <p bold="true">Chapter Tips</p>
            <p>
                -Immersive Engineering Excavator is unable to work, since it breaks the modpack oregen. Digital Miner and Void Miner are the alternatives later on.
            </p>
            <p> 
                -Tech Reborn Blast Furnace, along with IE Arc Furnace, are the only ways to melt down some elements due to their high melting point. The first also shows real melting point of each, if below 1200Celsius, basic furnaces can be used aswell.
            </p>
            <p>
                -Aroma1997's Dimensional World oregen has been disabled, no ore will spawn in there, it is not meant to be a mining dimension but instead a place for generating energy, setting up farms, testing stuff, etc. Sun never sets in this dimension.
            </p>
            <p>
                -Obsidian TNT renamed to ANFO, which now has a 100 blast power, useful to blow up mountains.
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
            <p>
                -Osmium processing reworked, no more x5 ore multiplying, now it is a high tier material thus it is not longer used in many low recipes.
            </p>
            <p>
                -Solar and Wind generators now produce x2 and x3 more power, but they are also more difficult to craft. 
            </p>
            <p color="#FF4F4F">
                There is a config bug and they output now the same amount of power, this issue will be fixed asap.
            </p>
            <p>
                -Wasteland biomes are hazardous to the player, radiation may kill you in a few minutes if you dont go prepared. Mining there is no longer possible until you are able to counter it. 
            </p>
        </page>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="chapter4">
        <page>
            <title bold="true" underline="true">The Late Game</title>
            <p>
                There are many factors to measure how far you have progressed on this modpack, like powergen, mining production, chemistry and nuclear stuff. But once you set up your AE2 network you are entering a new tech level, you need one to deal with all the materials and craftings in a efficient way.
                You should set up your AE2 network in your main base, as you can now teleport to different places there is no more need to create multiple bases to host your mining facilities. Now its the moment to experiment with new ways of generating power in bigger quantities, but you can also keep improving the renewable generators output.
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
        	 <p bold="true">Chapter Tips</p>
            <p>
                -Simple Void World dimension is always at noon, as opposed to Aroma1997's permanent day, no mobs will spawn in there so it is a good place for experimenting and late game setups.
            </p>
            <p>
                NuclearCraft cooling capacity of materials reworked, vanilla and basic metals are much more inefficient at cooling to the point they are almost useless. On the other hand, materials like helium, enderium and cryotheum have it increased.
            </p>
            <p>
                -Molecullar Transformer is currently the only way to obtain Iridium.
            </p>
        </page>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="chapter5">
        <page>
            <title bold="true" underline="true">The End Game</title>
            <p>
                At this point you should have a constant stream of materials coming to your base, with several automatic mining outposts located in certain profitable biomes which will provide you with key materials for the end game. 
                Now crafting process gets more complicated and maybe even tedious, with more extended craftings and lots of chained crafts, to speed up the process it is highly recommended setting up an automatized crafting system. 
                As late machines drain larger chunks of power to do their jobs, you will need to increase first your powergen capabilities, Nuclear reactors will prove helpful at this moment.
                This is also the right moment to start with space exploration now that you have acquired enough knowledge in all the previous fields.
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
            <p bold="true">Chapter Tips</p>
            <p>
                -Dilithium Ore can be only found at some rare Asteroids (in a similar fashion to Star Trek).
            </p>
            <p>
                -Asteroids have been reworked to make them much more interesting to discover and exploit, there are 10 types of asteroids of different sizes and composition, they contain 15 different ores, some of them very rare or unobtainable on the Earth (Overworld). 
            </p>
            <p>
                -Environmental Tech Tier 1 Void Ore Miner drains 26MRF/Block at very high rate per tick with only 1MRF energy buffer. This presents technical difficulties to the player that cannot be overcome until the End Game. However this is the only way to override the modpack oregen since it mines directly from The Void.
            </p>
            <p>
                -XNet Advanced Cables can transfer up to 500000 RF/t
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
        </page>
        <page>
            <space height="250"/>
            <p>
                Thank you for playing my modpack.
            </p>
                <p align="right">Tenosko</p>
        </page>

    </chapter>
    <chapter id="chapter6">
        <page>
            <title bold="true" underline="true">Modpack Goals</title>
            <p color="#FF4F4F">
                List in process...
            </p>
        </page>
    </chapter>
</book>