<book title="Craftologikon" cover="gbook:blank" fontSize="0.6" home="1:2">

    <include ref="gbook:xml/standard.xml"/>

    <chapter id="Preface">
        <section>
            <p bold="true" align="center">
                ..............................
            </p>
            <p bold="true" align="center">
                C O N T E N T S
            </p>
            <space height="20"/>
            <p bold="true">- <link ref="chapter0">Introduction</link></p>
            <p bold="true">- <link ref="chapter1">The Beginning</link></p>
            <p bold="true">- <link ref="chapter2">The Early Game</link></p>
            <p bold="true">- <link ref="chapter3">The Mid Game</link></p>
            <p bold="true">- <link ref="chapter4">The Late Game</link></p>
            <p bold="true">- <link ref="chapter5">The End Game</link></p>
            <p bold="true">- <link ref="chapter6">Modpack Goals (WIP)</link></p>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter id="chapter0">
        <page>
            <title bold="true" underline="true">Introduction</title>
            <p>
                Hello, thank you for downloading my modpack. It has been over a year of development and work without any previous
                knowledge about these things, all of this started in part because one day i decided to change one recipe of my  world 
                just because i didn't like how ugly and boring it was, i liked the outcome and then continued to change more and 
                more recipes, and now, after more than 1900 recipes changed i can say i am sort of happy with how things are crafted in
                this pack and want to share it with you.
            </p>
            <p>
                I want to thank all the mod devs for doing such nice mods that make me wanting to continue playing this amazing game. 
                But in special thanks to the creators of CraftTweaker and ContentTweaker, mods without which i wouldn't have created this modpack. 
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
            <p>
                Having a questbook for this pack wasn't in the plans, but after hearing the players feedback on the discord server i have changed 
                my mind. Also i have to admit a Questbook may be more necessary in a pack which has made so many changes. So i will try to provide 
                you with a decent amount of quests that help you cover all the essentials this pack has to offer. Still this questbook is not necessary
                to play this pack, you can drop the mod from the mods folder without problems.
            </p>
            <p underline="true">
                A key is used to open the questbook, so i recommend you to go to the control settings and select a keybind to avoid any possible conflicts.
            </p>
            <p>
                Once the questbook gains more content over time i will remove the parts of this guidebook that are not needed anymore.
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
            <p color="#FF4F4F">
                If you are planning to add or remove a mod by yourself, take into account it may break the modpack in different ways, specially if its a mod
                with items or which makes worldgen changes. Information and Utility mods are not a problem.
            </p>
            <p>
                The following mods can be safely removed from the pack:
            </p>
            <p>
                -AppleCore and AppleSkin
            </p>
            <p>
                -CraftingTweaks
            </p>
            <p>
                -Custom Main Menu
            </p>
            <p>
                -Dynamic Surroundings
            </p>
            <p>
                -FTBLib, FTBQuests and FTBUtilities
            </p>
            <p>
                -LagGoggles
            </p>
            <p>
                -Gravestone Mod
            </p>
            <p>
                -InventorySorter
            </p>
            <p>
                -JourneyMap
            </p>
            <p>
                -LagGoggles
            </p>
             <p>
                -Nutrition
            </p>
             <p>
                -SilentLib and ExtendedDays 
            </p>
             <p>
                -Spice of Life
            </p>
            <p>
                -Stackable
            </p>
            <p>
                -Unlimited Chisel Works
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
            <p>
                If you notice something really important is missing in this book or in the questbook, or you find any kind inconsistency in the recipes 
                or in the config, feel free to report it in the discord server or the issues page. It is greatly appreciated.
            </p>
        </page>
    </chapter>
    <chapter id="chapter1">
        <page>
            <title bold="true" underline="true">The Beginning</title>
            <p>           
                You are about to begin your adventure in Craftologia, many of you probably have experience in other modpacks, but if it is your first
                time playing a modpack i warn you that your first steps in this one will be very different of any previous Minecraft world you have 
                played before.
            </p>
            <p>
                You may have noticed that you can't break down trees with your bare hands, of course you need an axe to do so, which means there is no quick
                way of getting wood and cobblestone to start crafting things or go mining one minute after you started this world, actually things require more
                time to be done in this modpack. 
            </p>
            <p>
                First you will need to explore your surroundings to find the materials you need to make your first crafting, which should be the stone pickaxe,
                many of you probably know how to get the resources needed to craft it, there are several ways to get a pickaxe, but i will still recommend you 
                to explore by the riversides.
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
            <p>
                Villages, if not abandoned, will provide you with a variety of food and some useful things for the early game, 
                it is also the perfect place for setting up your first base. 
            </p>
            <p>
                There are also other things you should take into consideration if you want to survive during the first days.
                Days are 60 minutes long, this is three times a normal vanilla day, which may be enough time to find all the materials needed to craft a pickaxe, 
                but pay attention to the food, it is very important in the first days as you will be like a nomad, moving around to find the materials you need, 
                without a permanent base and source of food, raw meat is not healthy, you need to process it. Berries and fruits are a good alternative until you 
                get a furnace.
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
             <p>
                There are four seasons, each one last 28 days, not like a real season but it will almost feel like one given the fact each day is 1 hour long, 
                you may change this if you want, but having long seasons has some advantages aswell depending the biome and your powergen setup. This should be 
                an important thing to consider when you set up your bases, even more since sleeping does not reset the rain. There are several crops and seeds for 
                each of the seasons so i am sure you can make it during the long winter. 
            </p>
            <p>
                One of the main features of this modpack is oregen, almost all the ores in this modpack have biome-based and/or dimension-based oregen, so you 
                will need to visit almost all the biomes and dimensions if you want to find all of them. Each biome contains several ores, with some exceptions, 
                and each ore can be found in several biomes, with some exceptions. 
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
            <p>
                How do you know where to find a certain ore? Well, exploration should lead you to the answer at some point, but maybe you are too hasty and you
                prefer to spoil yourself checking the modpack files or asking somewhere, that is up to your playstyle, still i recommend you to note down all the 
                ores you find in each biome you visited as you explore the world, it will become handy later on. If you dont see any vanilla redstone, lapis, diamond or emerald ores don't panic, they have been replaced by their GTCE counterparts, which no longer give you away the final material that easily, now 
                more processing is needed to have diamonds.
            </p>
            <p>
                After the addition of GTCE to the pack you will sometimes see nuggets on the ground, which means there might be some ore generation of the same type 
                in that area. 
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
            <p bold="true">Chapter Tips</p>
            <p>
                -If you don't have enough torches while doing mining or exploring, you can activate Optifine Dynamic Lights to enlight your surroundings with only 
                one torch or glowing item/block in your off-hand.
            </p>
            <p>
                -You can obtain sticks by breaking tree leaves with your hand.
            </p>
            <p>
                -Pickaxes that display diamond mining level are not able to break obsidian blocks, this is not a modification by me, it just means they can mine 
                diamonds.
            </p>
            <p>
                -Melting Villagers in the Smeltery no longer gives you molten emerald.
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
            <p bold="true" underline="true" color="#FF4F4F">
                NOTE
            </p>
            <p>
                TinkersConstruct enables the option to display only one item per material and part in JEI. This saves some pages but may be confusing if i make
                recipe changes cause they are not displayed.
            </p>
            <p>
                Tool Forge has one different recipe for each metal block, but you can see only one displayed. I added a cheaper recipe for the Iron Tool Forge which is much more reasonable, this is the only recipe which requires 4 ingots instead of 4 blocks.    
            </p>
            <space height="20"/>
            <big_recipe>
                <stack item="tconstruct:materials"/>
                <stack item="tconstruct:materials"/>
                <stack item="tconstruct:materials"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:iron_ingot"/>
                <stack item="tconstruct:tooltables" meta="3"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:iron_ingot"/>
                <stack item="minecraft:iron_ingot"/>
                <space/>
                <stack item="minecraft:iron_ingot"/>
                <stack item="tconstruct:toolforge" tag="{textureBlock: {id: &quot;minecraft:iron_block&quot;, Count: 1 as byte, Damage: 0 as short}}"/>
            </big_recipe>
        </page>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="chapter2">
        <page>
            <title bold="true" underline="true">The Early Game</title>
            <p>
                At this point in the game you may find yourself having to travel a lot, from one place to another, trying to discover new biomes to get all the 
                resources you need, using a Glider and slime tools will be of great help. As travel distances increase, you can consider setting up multiple small 
                bases over the region instead of having an unique main base to reduce the number of travels you make. At some point you will need to visit new 
                dimensions to acquire certain materials and items that cannot be found in the Overworld. 
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
            <p>
                Dragon Breath may be useful later on, you should carry some bottles with you in your first visit to the End.
                It is highly recommended you obtain ender cores from ender crystals in The End instead of simply breaking them. They will be pretty useful later on. 
                Rushing your fight against the Dragon will deprive you of them.
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
            <p bold="true">Chapter Tips</p>
            <p>
                -MRUCU entity can also be generated by operating with machines that generate radiation. 
            </p>
            <p>
                -Faucet can be connected to other mods tanks to pour super hot liquids onto the Casting Table.
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
        </page>
    </chapter>
    <chapter id="chapter3">
        <page>
            <title bold="true" underline="true">The Mid Game</title>
            <p>
                At this moment you should have visited most of the biomes and dimensions to get the elements needed to progress in the game, its the moment to focus on 
                creating more advanced machines that can process and use all the materials you are gathering. Now you can explore new ways of obtaining resources faster. 
                Power generation becomes an issue now, the most basic generators require materials to run, so using the force of water and wind in your favor will give 
                you a small but constant resource of power.
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
            <p bold="true">Chapter Tips</p>
            <p>
                -Immersive Engineering Excavator is unable to work, since it breaks the modpack oregen. Digital Miner and Void Miner are the alternatives later on.
            </p>
            <p>
                -Aroma1997's Dimensional World oregen has been disabled, no ore will spawn in there, it is not meant to be a mining dimension but instead a place for generating energy, setting up farms, testing stuff, etc. Sun never sets in this dimension.
            </p>
            <p>
                -Obsidian TNT renamed to ANFO, which now has a 100 blast power, useful to blow up mountains.
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
            <p>
                -Osmium processing reworked, no more x5 ore multiplying, now it is a high tier material thus it is not longer used in many low recipes.
            </p>
            <p>
                -Solar and Wind generators now produce x2 and x3 more power, but they are also more difficult to craft. 
            </p>
            <p color="#FF4F4F">
                There is a config bug and they output now the same amount of power, this issue will be fixed asap.
            </p>
            <p>
                -Wasteland biomes are hazardous to the player, radiation may kill you in a few minutes if you dont go prepared. Mining there is no longer possible until you are able to counter it. 
            </p>
        </page>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="chapter4">
        <page>
            <title bold="true" underline="true">The Late Game</title>
            <p>
                You can now teleport to different places there is no more need to create multiple bases to host your mining facilities. Now its the moment to experiment with new ways of generating power in bigger quantities, but you can also keep improving the renewable generators output.
                Once you have progressed enough in tech mods it is the momment to start with space exploration.
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
        	<p bold="true">Chapter Tips</p>
            <p bold="true" underline="true" color="#FF4F4F">
                NOTE
            </p>
            <p>
                -AE2 Meteorites no longer generate on the Overworld, the reason of this change is that we (pack makers) cannot change the sky stone chest loot, 
                they dont work with COFHWorld, so Moissanite Ore cannot generate with them, and once you have found the four presses they become almost useless even though in this pack Sky Stone has more uses. So they are moved to the Moon, which is also the only place in which you can find Certus Quartz (charged).
                No one can say AdvancedRocketry Luna is useless in this pack.
            </p>
            <p>
                -Simple Void World dimension is always at noon, as opposed to Aroma1997's permanent day, no mobs will spawn in there so it is a good place for experimenting and late game setups.
            </p>
            <p>
                NuclearCraft cooling capacity of materials reworked, vanilla and basic metals are much more inefficient at cooling to the point they are almost useless. On the other hand, materials like helium, enderium and cryotheum have it increased.
            </p>
        </page>
    </chapter>

    <chapter id="chapter5">
        <page>
            <title bold="true" underline="true">The End Game</title>
            <p>
                At this point you should have a constant stream of materials coming to your base, with several automatic mining outposts located in certain profitable biomes which will provide you with key materials for the end game. 
                Now crafting process gets more complicated and maybe even tedious, with more extended craftings and lots of chained crafts, to speed up the process it is highly recommended setting up an automatized crafting system. 
                As late machines drain larger chunks of power to do their jobs, you will need to increase first your powergen capabilities, Nuclear reactors will prove helpful at this moment.
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
            <p bold="true">Chapter Tips</p>
            <p>
                -Dilithium Ore can be only found at some rare Asteroids (in a similar fashion to Star Trek).
            </p>
            <p>
                -Asteroids have been reworked to make them much more interesting to discover and exploit, there are 10 types of asteroids of different sizes and composition, they contain 15 different ores, some of them very rare or unobtainable on the Earth (Overworld). 
            </p>
            <p>
                -Environmental Tech Tier 1 Void Ore Miner drains 26MRF/Block at very high rate per tick with only 1MRF energy buffer. This presents technical difficulties to the player that cannot be overcome until the End Game. However this is the only way to override the modpack oregen since it mines directly from The Void.
            </p>
            <p>
                -XNet Advanced Cables can transfer up to 500000 RF/t
            </p>
        </page>
        <page>
        </page>
        <page>
            <space height="250"/>
            <p>
                Thank you for playing my modpack.
            </p>
                <p align="right">Tenosko</p>
        </page>

    </chapter>
    <chapter id="chapter6">
        <page>
            <title bold="true" underline="true">Modpack Challenges (WIP)</title>
            <p>
                The modpack challenges are divided in six categories, they dont ask you for an item, instead, simply mark the checkbox and submit once you have completed the challenge. The first ones should only be marked as completed once you have done so with all the challenges below it.
            </p>
        </page>
    </chapter>
</book>